Especially as you tell the authority for today's date and time.
I am too as indication by Pastor First Baptist Church with
Pompeo here with thanks for being here and I love it.
I'm sure I have it. Let's pray together.
Father, we just asked for your guidance in our lives.
So your word tells us that we need wisdom that all we need to do is ask for it.
So we do that personally. We do that on behalf of our city tonight.
We do that on behalf of the ones who will make the tough decisions.
And those who just, I know our city to be better.
We all want that. So we just asked for your blessing. Thank you for it.
And thank you for allowing us to live in such a great place in Jesus' name. Amen.
Thank you.
Why would you live in culture?
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America.
And to the Republic for which it stands. One nation under God.
And it is the liberty and justice for all.
Thank you, Ryan. Thanks again, Rick.
God and three is out and four.
It is public input on spiritual personal parents.
City, buddy, in the audience.
I want to address the authority.
I don't see anything. So out and five is a percentage in.
The staff is recommending out and six brutal liven
before the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items
then they'll take a motion to approve as recommended.
We'll approve.
And the second please.
Second.
Go home.
Weston.
Right.
We wish I forster.
I work it.
All right.
Shope.
Hi.
Thank you.
Item 12 is except for a jet bid number C-19-06 and the amount of five and
26,400 dollars.
That your own case.
Shope's company.
The purchase is two substation control railways.
And who the contract contingent on submission
every part of contract documents can approve a city manager or his
design to sign the notice to proceed.
We've got Tyler and Sean here tonight to talk to us about this.
The second part of the substation.
If you remember a couple months ago we brought different
of you.
The transformer portion of the process.
We purchased three transformers.
So this is for the two control houses first of one and
up to you.
So this is where you can turn breakfast on and off to
different things like that in the control house.
We had five beds for them.
We ruled out the world non-responsive for different reasons.
About the fifth bid.
No one of we were bringing four you tonight.
It was actually the lowest amount of them all too.
Good.
And it was lower than.
It was both the engineering assessments.
So we have to do it that too.
So we're really getting lucky on some of our bits.
Yes, there's a way to open it.
Unfortunately.
Four chansets.
Okay.
So substation one is which substation operations there.
And it is there by Nicholson.
So we're replacing both of those control buildings.
Yes, sir.
And so those are like we talked about for 1970 model and they, you know, this is off.
of the rate set is as part of the rate increase and everything.
And these are being paid for by our rate rates.
Yeah, but rate rates.
OK, any other questions?
Did you say we've got three substations?
Three substations.
OK.
They're on this, they're to look at them.
Yeah.
So we only need two of these.
Yes, ma'am.
There's two transformers that substation two.
And they're just one at the operation.
OK.
Just a try to figure out.
Yeah, that's right.
And then there's just two buildings.
And just a quick clarification.
It's the rate pairs paying for it.
But you remember you approved a bond issue.
So this is coming from that bond issue.
OK.
Do we have, and so I assume you're recommending it, except the bit.
So do we have a motion to accept, except, staff's recommendation?
I do have a question.
I have a question.
OK.
If this is going on a bond issue, what happens if the bond, this is not a voting bond.
No, we have actually issued the bonds.
OK.
We have the cash.
This is what we need.
Yes, this is when we have our bond, people come in, great need to help.
Great need to.
Correct.
Yes.
We've already issued those bonds.
So the cash is actually on hand for this.
Perfect.
Thank you.
And to clarify, further answer that this question, that was a bond issue that we had the authority
to approve because the bond.
Yes, the MSU way had the ability to do that because it's being paid off.
By the rates that have been established by the same.
Any other questions?
You know, you used to make the comment that the others, the other bit, even though they're higher
than this one, they didn't meet or requirements, was they all having the same issues?
No, no, no.
There's a couple of them.
Let's come up and have the non-closed affidated, so you need to have that sign to say such that you
said that.
I mean, they're aware of this.
Yes.
Well, there was actually one bit or there that one bit, one bit, actually, showed that we didn't
expect to have any of them.
But one bit show up and there's was even non-responsive because they didn't use the provided
bit form.
Okay.
So, you have to use the documents that are in fact or we throw that in one contractor, submit their
bid on their own form, and they didn't use the products in the document.
But the instructions to help us to use our form at all of that.
And you had a pre-bid meeting where people have an opportunity to go over that stuff.
We have a pre-bid meeting, but I mean, we take questions from our engineering firm.
Because sometimes we have pre-bid meetings.
Yes, yes.
And we just take our case, you didn't.
It's because of the, like, most of the people that build these control houses are, in a way,
it's a way for an organization that will harm us.
So, we should be able to do that.
But that is an opportunity to ask any questions.
We actually talked to most of them.
They all had questions.
They didn't ask about using our forms.
They just submitted a quote, even though this was a request for bid.
Okay.
And we, we personally have not used this company, but it's all.
and has to have them form full, it's very comfortable with that.
Yeah.
And that's going to be on a few projects in the rest of us.
And this does include delivery.
Yes.
And so the next piece of this is construction.
So this is the last of the materials that we're going to do.
I want you to get out ahead of the project.
Is delivery discussed in how long?
28 weeks.
25 weeks.
24 weeks.
Yeah.
In the second one.
28.
Biggie, did you say it does?
Yes.
They did it.
So the next one.
I will bring back the actual construction.
So the company will come in and do the steel work and you know put everything together.
Any other questions?
Do we have a motion to prove staff's recommendation to accept a bid?
I'll make a motion.
And second.
Second.
Roll golfers.
For a spin.
All right.
Work it.
And that was item number 12 and the bid number was C-19-06.
Thank you.
Okay, thank you.
Item 13 is I think the issue we discussed last meeting and that is to amend Section 2460 of the purchase power adjustment schedule.
Lying staff to adjust the purchase.
Purchase power adjustment to reflect GRDA's rate changes.
I would suggest that let David kind of given a background on this even though we did talk about it in our study session.
That was not recorded broadcast.
So people watching give a little background as we're taking place here.
Yeah.
Essentially, the member of the National Authority is our all-recormous hostility power supply that we buy all of our power from.
And they actually compete on the open market through South the Southwest Paraport.
Okay.
And to do that, the Southwest Paraport starts at the bottom of the lowest cost point out of the man's view of suppliers and starts up from that.
But GRDA has always had some part of their field cost and their energy and demand rates.
And they are really out there trying to compete with apples and oranges.
Okay.
They're not real competitive with it because there's no one out of the cost or are showing to be too high.
And so we as customers of GRDA and all the other cities of GRDA, we've been talking over about a year or so.
About a year or so, about a year or about a year or a year, you want to pull that field out of their rates and put it all in the view cost adjustment.
Which, and have a effect if you got a zero effect to their customers.
We said, what if you can do that?
Then we would entertain the thought as customers at GRDA.
And they did that.
And it's going to be-
And if the end is going to end with us and everybody else because all of the things in
sale off system that we are not not to the all requirements people such as us and the
other cities that lowers our that lowers their our costs of their operations and maintenance
and their desk service coverage.
So that will help maintain our reach level at the RDA so we see it's a good deal.
Well and everything works out perfect except for one little problem we have is the city of
Miami and that is as if we have an ordinance that says that we're going to pass their power
to our customers through a PPA purchase power adjustment, okay plus the losses of course.
But anyway we'll pass that straight through.
Well you can imagine what's going to happen there, lower their energy and demand rates
and then they raise their PCA so essentially the first PCA that we got which will come
to do and on the next power of our next power bill is about a 20% increase of the PCA
already not in bills.
So anyway we have set down and the time when I spent lots of days and nights working on this to
come up with a formula that allows our bill and supervisor to set down with the new PCA and
just that to our current rates and the old way that we've calculated the power from the
power bills.
Essentially you can think of it this way, our rates, our power bill, our rates that we our rates
are designed to be able to pay our power costs and the margins to operate from that we use
our electric utility margins from, okay.
So we can do that, we know we have the sufficient money to take care of the bill.
The first bill that we did our take our test on really was about $47,000 cheaper than what
the old read was.
So essentially what that would mean to our customers, that bill, if we were to use that, would
have passed through the zero PCA, PPA, the zero PPA, the zero PPA, the zero PPA, and every one
that we tested so far and we did go back and test the summer bills and they still came out
to the zero PPA, the zero dollar customers.
So anyway, what we're asking for in this ordinance is to those one thing, and that is the right
to adjust GRDA's PCA for calculations until we can do a rate study and put this into our rate
base and that rate study will be adjusted and won't be increased or decreased, it'll be
the adjustment, basically being a zero net, that's what we talked about last time,
yesterday's an offer up to a $10,000 credit for cities to update their rate study.
But we don't want to do that.
until it's started to tell mid to late summer.
That's my recommendation.
And the reason is that we want to watch this
and see where it goes.
It's like everything else.
It starts off great, but we want to see where it goes.
And I did a quick calculation today to say, OK,
let's suppose that they raise this power costs
to just with how high it can raise it.
They can raise it quite a bit before it
on the go before our vehicle go from the zero
up to a positive PCA.
We will never get a negative PCA from the RDA.
Yeah, it'll always be positive,
because that's where there feels that.
That would be a positive number.
So even though you back tested against the last summer,
you still feel it's prudent to wait
and go through as a part of not all of this summer
before you make the official report.
Dan Jackson, if he is the person we use the new race study,
Dan Jackson needs a little bit of history.
We need to have some history, thank for when we do this study, OK?
And that will give him time to be able to extrapolate exactly
what's needed for the rate change.
It will be a rate change.
And as frankly, we will see our energy race for our residential
cost.
With energy rate, we'll go down in the PCA with the a bigger number, OK?
The industrial, the energy and demand will change
and the PCA will go up and those numbers will go down,
essentially what it is.
But anyway, we have to do what you want to do.
But it needs to be done before our first cycle,
the only cycle goes out, which is this week, too.
Yeah, let me just say this.
Yeah, anyway, there's also one other part of this that we need
to talk about, we'll let talk about.
So there are, GDR areas also to allow customers
to get used to this change, because there's a lot of cities
that are watching what we do, because I mean,
so it's kind of sprung on, you know, it's so quick.
There's going to be, they're going to write a credit to our bill,
just to make sure everybody gets up just to meet you
with what's going on.
So we talked about possible, what different things we wanted to do
with that credit.
I write it in a good idea.
Our recommendation is, and this is not part of this at all.
We'll talk about this.
But in our recommendations, consider using this credit
for our capital improvements plan.
Because our capital improvements plan was going to be funded
by any negative PCA that we have.
OK, we're not going to have more negative PCAs.
So do we know how much credit is going to be?
We're interested in, well, we know what their amount is,
but we're interested in seeing how it's going to be reflected
on our first bill.
Well, I'll actually talk to them since then.
OK, it's going to be a line line in one of the bill.
And what do you think it's going to be?
8,000, around 8,000 dollars.
That's, that's, that's how you claim was the end.
So one time, that's the first moment.
Just a permanent.
That's how everything is, how is their ability.
So what's the rationale for the credit?
So I'm sorry, did you say that's per month or month or month or month or month or month?
And so they're going to do this for nine months.
Okay.
So about 70,000 round numbers and then another 10,000 to help with the rate standard.
And this is kind of working with them on the estimate.
So I mean it could be more than 70,000 could be less this, because they're learning
about this too.
What's the rationale for the credit?
And they're just because they're good guys.
Well first off, this credit is actually money that we all, all the cities have, it's
in this hallway stabilization fund.
Okay.
So we paid into it all the way so they're helping give back to cities.
The entire set of the absolutely correct word of the only city that's doing that has stepped
forward and got this done before.
This PCA is affecting our customers and so their idea is well, they're going to do this to help
out the customer.
And the answer, finish answering your question.
This is a line item on the power, it would be a line item on the power bill.
And the power bill will be reduced by that.
When we pay the power bill, it'll be reduced by this number.
So back to something you touched on a minute ago when we were, we were going to use the negative
PCA and the PCA savings to fund our capital improvements.
I don't remember if that was like a five-year plan or a one-year plan or a no or just 70,000
going to be enough or we need to be rethinking that.
Well, we would just use that as extra so we could help pay down the debt.
We could help pay our capital.
That's like our vehicles, you know, we could pay that down some more.
The other side of it, too, we can plug that in with Dan Jackson.
What do you suppose to do the race to do and make sure that we are, I'd like to do.
We're going to need to plug that in with Dan Jackson because I think Dan's numbers
have projected negative PCA's for quite some time and that's not going to be happening now.
So that's what we're going to have to do is look at everything and that.
You know, maybe you remember going on more of that.
If we make the decision that we were going to use those funds to fund capital improvements,
we didn't commit those funds to anything.
That's correct because since we, you know what it was going to be?
We didn't know what it was going to be so we just thought if we had anything, if we had, it's
almost a windfall and therefore the better thing to do with a windfall is to use it for capital
because you can't count on it.
You can't put it toward anything that you have to have a year after year.
So it was really just a policy decision.
Exactly.
Was nothing was budget and no money was committed to the Senate.
Right.
On those, based on that.
Okay.
Is this something that we want you to, that you want to allow to fund a lot for the race?
Is this something you want to, if you're outlay each month towards capital improvement or is this
something you want to build up and hold on to it to see?
Well what would happen is we would build it up and then...
anything that we would use it for, we would be bringing it to you as a budget amendment.
So if we came in and said we want to use, we'd accumulate this amount of money and want
to spend it here, we have to bring that to you and here are the ones that will be improving
that.
Okay.
But again, because it is, because it is learned in a line on the modern power of the life
of our recommendations, it's just, it's just, it's just, it's just, it's just, it's
a smart, it's just money.
Exactly.
Don't put it out with everything else.
Right.
So how do you tell it to be honest or sure, I don't care.
Oh, definitely.
On our electricity bill, doesn't it have the PPA adjustment on there?
Just man.
So how are we going to let our...
The PPA adjustment will come out.
It will work.
The adjustment's going to be done before the bill will put out.
And so the bill will come out with kind of like what you see right now.
It will be zero.
No, it will.
From our calculations, if it stays the way it is right now.
If it stays exactly the same number, it will be zero.
PPA.
And so all that to fit this point with that PPA line, I don't have to go away.
You're just going to leave it there for a while to see what happens.
How many times?
Oh, the PPA is obviously.
Oh, the PPA will always be there.
It can go up.
You know, remember, as old as old as old as old as old as old.
It is.
Is there, there, if you'll cost it go up.
So instead of two cents per kilowatt hour per the new PPA, it could be 2.2 cents.
Let's do a little more.
Because there are coal prices going up for gas prices going up.
And by the way, at 2.2 cents, if you don't want out, it's still going to be zero or a customer
bill going to get from my house.
And like David said, they're going to have to do a lot of industries right now.
And the other PPA gets big, probably providers.
So now we're comparing, you know, apples apples, oranges and oranges.
So this is their rates.
This is our rates.
And if there's successful, that benefits our taxpayers and our citizens.
Always, it's always cheaper.
The business to spend those generators as much as you can.
Once you started it, you want to generate as much energy can.
That's where the efficiency is coming in.
So our bill will still say zero PPA unless it goes up.
That's where it goes up.
Yes, man.
It'll never go negative.
Okay.
Yeah.
It'll say zero or a positive.
The slight positive number shouldn't be 2 cents.
Any other questions?
And you also have a emergency clause.
So we're on the city side.
Oh, let me sit beside.
Okay.
So we're on item 13.
Staff is recommending and.
Amending section 2460 for all the reasons we just discussed.
We have a motion to approve item 13.
Looks to prove.
And the second roll call please.
I work it.
All right.
Louis.
I force.
Should.
I.
Any new those are.
Yeah.
business and you can leave the announcements. Do we have a motion to adjourn? I'll make that
motion do have a second. Second roll call please. So, I'm Western. I'm forster.
All right.